Cheryl Crawford Collection
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
- Sheet Music, 1862-1951
  - Amorita, 1920 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - At Sundown (Love is Calling Me Home), 1927 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Auf Wiedersehen, My Dear, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Away Down South in Heaven,1927 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Body and Soul, 1941 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Bright was the Day, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Broadway Rose, 1920 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - By the Way (I'm Still in Love with You), 1929 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - By the Sapphire Sea, 1922 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Carnegie Hall, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Chiquita, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Come Back, Little Genie, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Crazy Words Crazy Tune Vo-Do-De-o, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Egyptian Moon, 1920 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Everything is Peaches Down in Georgia, 1918 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Feather Your Nest, 1920 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Fighting on the Home Front, Wins, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Fit as a Fiddle, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Four Walls, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Get Out and Get Under the Moon, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Gondoliera Veneziana, 1925 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Good-Bye (Addio), 1905 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Here's to All Your Dreams, undated.; 2 copies (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Here's to Your Illusions, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - How Could We Be Wrong, 1933 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Hypnotized, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - I Love No One But You, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - I Saw No Shadow, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - I Still See Elisa, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - I Wanna Go Where You Go, 1925 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - I Want to Meander in the Meadow,1929 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - I'll Follow My Secret Heart, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - I'm Beginning to See the Light, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - (I'm Tellin' the Bird, Tellin' the Bees) How I Love You, 1926 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - I've Got Me, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - If I Only Had You Back Again, 1926 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - If Love Were All, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - In a Little Garden (You Made Paradise), 1926 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Jealous, 1924 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Johnny's Song, undated.; 2 items (Box Oversize)
  - Just a Memory, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Just a Night for Meditation, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - Just Like a Melody out of the Sky, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - Kiss Me, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - Laughing at Life, 1930 (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - Lazy Day, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 47)
  - Little Log Cabin of Dreams, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 48)
  - Little White Lies, 1930 (Box 13, Folder 49)
  - Manhattan, 1925 (Box 13, Folder 50)
  - Memories of France, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 51)
  - Mighty Lak' a Rose, 1901 (Box 13, Folder 52)
  - Mine, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 53)
  - My Blackbirds Are Bluebirds Now, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 54)
  - My Gypsy Rhapsody, 1933 (Box 13, Folder 55)
  - Old Man Sunshine (Little Boy Bluebird), 1928 (Box 13, Folder 56)
  - One Two Three, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 57)
  - Op in Me Ansom, 1904 (Box 13, Folder 58)
  - Out of the Dawn, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 59)
  - Pilgrim's Sing, 1899 (Box 13, Folder 60)
  - Poor Papa (He's Got Nothin' at All), 1926 (Box 13, Folder 61)
  - Precious Little Thing Called Love, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 62)
  - Puddin' Head Jones, 1933 (Box 13, Folder 63)
  - Put Your Arms Where They Belong, 1926 (Box 13, Folder 64)
  - Ramona, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 65)
  - Sandy Jane, undated (Box 13, Folder 66)
  - Say It Again, 1926 (Box 13, Folder 67)
  - Sea Fever, 1914 (Box 13, Folder 68)
  - Song of India, 1912 (Box 13, Folder 69)
  - Sunday, 1926 (Box 13, Folder 70)
  - Sweet Child (I'm Wild about You), 1925 (Box 13, Folder 71)
  - Swingin' Down the Lane, 1923 (Box 13, Folder 72)
  - Tales from the Vienna Woods, 1941 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Tell Me. 1919 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - That Old Black Magic. 1942 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - The Bells of St. Mary, 1927 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - The New Moon, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - The Song I Love, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - The Two of Us,1926 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - The World is Your Balloon, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Then I'll Be Happy, 1925 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - There But For You God, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - There's a Cabin in the Pines, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - This is a Changing World, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Ting-a-ling, 1926 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Together, 2 copies. 1928 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Touch of Your Hand, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Truly (I Love You), 1930 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Twelve O'Clock Waltz, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Under a Texas Moon, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Unless Your Heart is Mine, 1934 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - What Do We Do on a Dewy-dew-dewy Day, 1927 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - When the Real Thing Comes Your Way, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - When Your Hair Has Turned to Silver, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Whispering, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Who Says There Ain't No Santa Claus, undated (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Who Wouldn't, 1926 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Yankee Rose, 1926 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - You Want Lovin (But I Want Love), 1929 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Ziguener, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Any Little Girl, That's a Nice Girl, is the Right Girl, 1910 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Any Little Girl, That's a Nice Girl, is the Right Girl, 1910 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Casey Jones the Brave Engineer, 1909 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Cecile Waltz,1914 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Experiment, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Good Man is Hard to Find, 1918 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Isn't It Heavenly, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - It's a Long Long Way to Tipperary, 1912 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - It's Bad For Me, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Little Brown Jug, 1869 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Lorraine (My Beautiful Alsace Lorraine), 1917 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Mediterranean Madness, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Musical Gem, 1893 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Nymph Errant, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Physician, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Put On Your Old Grey Bonnet, 1909 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Sack Waltz, 1862 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Secret Love, undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Somewhere a Voice is Calling, undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Till the Sands of the Desert Grow Cold, 1911 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - What's the Matter with Father, 1910 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - When Johnny Comes Marching Home, undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - You Were There, 1935 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous unidentified, undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
- Sound Recordings, 1945-1970
  This collection contains 44 titles, comprised of 90 discs. The recordings are arranged alphabetically by the title of the disc or discs. The materials are dated 1945-1970, with the bulk of the records dated 1962-1970. Most of the records are 33 1/3 rpm, although there are several 78 rpm.
  Several of the recordings are musicals productions, including Brigadoon, Porgy and Bess, Camelot, and Johnny Johnson. There are also two interviews on record.
  Please provide advance notice if interested in using the sound recordings. The staff will arrange for the appropriate equipment to be placed in the Reading Room.
  - Alice in Wonderland, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Anyone Can Whistle, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Ballads of the Civil War, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Bentley on Brecht, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Blackbirds of 1928, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Brecht on Brecht, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Brigadoon, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Cabaret, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Camelot, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Carousel, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Celebration,1969 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Colette, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Company, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Der Jasager, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Hair, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - I Do! I Do! 1966 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - The Importance of Being Earnest, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Jennie, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Johnny Johnson, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Juno, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - London Show Hits, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Lost in the Stars, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Man of La Mancha, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Marc Blitzstein, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - No for an Answer, undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Oh! What a Lovely War, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - On a Clear Day You Can See Forever, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - 110° in the Shade, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - O Say Can You See, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Porgy and Bess, undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - The Prince and the Pauper, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Regina, 1953 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Riverwind, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Roberta, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Saint Louis Woman, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Songs of the Civil War, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Strange Interlude, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Sweet Charity (Movie), 1970 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Sweet Charity (Stage), 1970 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Street Scene, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Tryout, undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Various Noel Coward Songs, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Wake Up and Dream, undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Zorba, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- General, 1931-1976
  There are twenty folders in this series, which is arranged alphabetically by folder title. The materials in this series are dated 1931 through 1976, with the bulk of the materials dated 1942 through 1974. There are 219 items in this series.
  Included are papers related to the Actors Studio which include programs, membership lists, and minutes, the Group Theatre, the American Reperatory Theatre, the Crawshank Company, and the lawsuit in which Crawford was engaged regarding The Diary of Anne Frank. There are clippings and papers discussing Tennessee Williams. There are also miscellaneous financial statements.
  There are several clippings and pages from Variety magazine. These are dated 1955-1968, and include several pages of the "Golden Jubilee" issue celebrating 50 years of American theater. These items are housed separately in an oversized box.
  - Actors Studio, 1968-1972.; 5 items (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Actors Studio, 1973.; 15 items (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Actors Studio, 1974-1976.; 10 items (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - American National Theatre Academy, 1949-1951.; 12 items (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - American Repertory Theatre, undated.; 2 items (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Articles, Crawford, 1940-1964.; 6 items (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Articles, Miscellaneous, 1961-1976.; 6 items (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Bijou Theatre, 1958-1959.; 28 items (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Chandler, Richard, 1968.; 1 item (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Crawshenk Company, 1959-1960.; 10 items (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Diary of Anne Frank Lawsuit, 1955-1958.; 12 items (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Financial Matters, 1943-1973.; 13 items (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Financial Statements, undated.; 4 items (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Group Theatre, 1931-1941.; 12 items (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - New Theatre, 1935.; 1 item (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Playwriting, 1937.; 5 items (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Props, 1957.; 7 items (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Reviews, 1947-1956.; 19 items (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Soviet Theater, 1945.; 5 items (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Theatrical Protective Union, 1970.; 1 item (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Variety Reviews, 1955-1968.; 6 items (Box Oversize)
  - Variety Reviews, 1956.; 4 items (Box Oversize)
  - Wildberg, John, 1942-1948.; 19 items (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Williams, Tennessee, 1951-1975.; 16 items (Box 24, Folder 22)
- Posters, 1933-1971
  This series is arranged alphabetically and includes 24 posters used to advertise various productions in which Crawford was involved.
  - Brigadoon, 1947 (Box 25)
  - Celebration, [1969] (Box 25)
  - Colette,1970 (Box 25)
  - Family Portrait, 1939 (Box 25)
  - Flahooley, 1951 (Box 25)
  - Jennie, 1963 (Box 25)
  - Love Life, 1948 (Box 25)
  - The Love Suicide at Schofield Barracks, [1972] (Box 25)
  - Marathon, [1933] (Box 25)
  - Men in White, 1933 (Box 25)
  - Mother Courage and her Children, 1963 (Box 25)
  - Oh Men! Oh Women! 1953 (Box 25)
  - One Touch of Venus, 1943 (Box 25)
  - Paint Your Wagon, 1951 (Box 25)
  - Porgy and Bess, 1942 (Box 25)
  - Regina, 1949 (Box 25)
  - The Rivalry, 1959 (Box 25)
  - The Rose Tattoo, 1951 (Box 25)
  - Shadow of a Gunman, 1958 (Box 25)
  - Strange Interlude,1963 (Box 25)
  - Sweet Bird of Youth, 1959 (Box 25)
  - The Tempest, 1945 (Box 25)
  - Three Sisters, 1963] (Box 25)
  - The Web and the Rock, undated (Box 25)